Minhong (Zed) Zhou Resume

Profile

• Email: minhongz@gmail.com

• Projects: https://github.com/mhzed

Canadian Citizenship

Introduction

I am a software industry veteran with 20+ years of experience. I've worked in environments ranging from startups to established Enterprises. Throughout my career I have always loved problem solving. For me the joy of work comes from solving challenging problems and helping others in the process. To be an effective problem solver, I have remained curious and kept myself up to date with the newest technologies. My career goal has always been to find more challenging problems to solve and be useful to others, and I hope my quest for this goal will land me at your company.

Work Experiences

EMC/DELL/OpenText (2012-now)

Senior Consultant Engineer in EMC's ECD division in Shanghai China, later acquired by DELL and then OpenText. Software architect for full text search product development in Documentum xPlore, cloud integration with Solr and ElasticSearch. Experienced in Apache Lucene and its ecosystem of products. Familiar with Natural Language Processing technologies. Lead the team to successfully deliver both on-premise software solutions and cloud search service solutions. Chair of China COE (Center of Excellence) patent committee while at EMC. Participated in the W3C XQuery/XPath standard committees.

Ubisoft (2010-2012)

Software lead for the network subsystem of a MMORPG in Ubisoft Chengdu China. Responsible for the server architecture and in game networking subsystem.

AirG (2003-2010)

Server team lead for the mobile social networking product. One of the earliest employees who helped the company to grow from thousands to millions of daily active users. Lead a team of developers to implement a horizontally scalable server farm to handle the traffic.

Pre 2003

Self employed, worked on various software contracts. Internships at Raytheon, Spectrum Signal Processing, Incognito Software, etc.

Education

Bachelor degree from SFU School Of Engineering Science in British Columbia Canada in 2000.

Technical skills summary

- Languages: Java, Javascript/Typescript, C++, Python, XQuery (project), C#, etc.
- Search: Lucene/Solr, NLP
- Databases: Mysql/PostgreSQL, MongoDB, xDB(XML database).
- API: REST, SOAP, Apache Thrift, GraphQL
- Cloud operating system: Docker, Kubernetes, CloudFoundry.
- Frontend: React(demo), Angular.
- Deep Learning: WordVec(demo), MNIST(demo).